# Glenn Bayes

# IT project manager

### PERSONAL SUMMARY

A multi-skilled project manager with over 27 years of experience in IT. Highly developed supervisory, management and technical skills. Very capable with a proven ability to ensure the effective execution of IT projects and programmes within budget, to provide IT services and systems that can reduce an organisation's overall cost base, increase market share and overall performance.

Extensive practical knowledge of complex IT and eCommerce systems, programme & project management, human capital management, business analysis, quality assurance, and support.

Experience and exposure to a range of financial instruments and life-cycles including listed futures and futures options, listed equities, foreign exchange.

Looking for a new and challenging position that will make best use of my existing skills & experience, and also further my professional development.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

## SABBATICAL Jan 2014 - Feb 2016

#### Health and Fitness

•	Sports First Aid Certifications	Nov 2014
•	Personal Trainer (ITEC 2)	Dec 2014
•	Sports Massage (ITEC 3)	May 2015
•	Relocate from UK to Spain	Aug 2015
•	Teaching English as Foreign Language (TEFL.ORG)	current

# CREDIT SUISSE

Jun 1997 - Nov 2013

Financial Services Industry - London, New York, Sydney

#### PROJECT MANAGER

I have performed various roles during this time. My most recent duties have been in IT management and project management.

#### Duties (Oct 2009 - Date):

- Responsible for programme budget in excess of USD\$11.5 million
- Responsible for all aspects of project and programme delivery including initiation, execution & monitoring, through closure
- Responsible for PMO activities and deliverables
- Responsible for operational and expense management
- Management of procurement activities
- Human capital management of a team of over 40, geographically dispersed, technical and non-technical staff
- Responsible for the selection, recruitment, remuneration, and training of new staff
- Responsible for on-going implementation of operational improvements and efficiencies
- Responsible for team adherence to & compliance with corporate guidelines, policy, and procedures
- Execute complex, non-routine and routine projects
- Report to the IT Director
- Have excellent time management, confidentiality & communication skills
- Responsible for the business analysis and project management of multi-asset, single dealer trading platform
- Responsible for global team of business analysts and support specialists
- Preparation of technical. administrative. and user documentation

#### **EXPERTISE**

Project management

Project Delivery

Financial control

Business analysis

IT management

Problem and issue management

Vendor management

System integration

Application development

Banking front, middle and backoffice operations

Client consultation

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

People skills

Leadership skills

Decision making

Financial management

Accountability

Honesty & integrity

Comfortable challenging 'status quo'

Flexible / adaptable

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

Glenn Bayes Carrer de La Vinya 14 Sant Miquel de Guanteres BARCELONA 08232

T: 937 882943 M: 659 255644 E: gbayes@mac.com

DOB: 26-May-1964 Driving license: Yes

Nationality: Australian/British Settlement: NIE registered

# Glenn Bayes

# IT project manager

#### **INTERESTS & HOBBIES**

Personal Training/Fitness

Nutrition/Food/Gastronomy

Yoga/Meditation

Foreign Languages

Gardening / DIY Maintenance

Photography

Classically Trained Musician

## WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

WESTPAC BANKING CORPORATION Aug 1995 – Jun 1996 Financial Services Industry – Sydney

TECH SPECIALIST, PROJECT MANAGER

DIGITAL EQUIPMENT CORPORATION
Host Based Application Consulting – Sydney

Nov 1994 – Aug 1995

APPLICATION SUPPORT, SYSTEM INTEGRATION, CLIENT CONSULTATIONS

*HUMAN SERVICES AND HEALTH* Oct 1986 – Nov 1994 Australian Federal Government – Sydney, Hobart, Canberra

SYSTEM MANAGER, SYSTEM SUPPORT, SYSTEM INTEGRATIONS, APPLICATION CUSTOMISATION, MANAGEMENT & SUPPORT

AUSTRALIAN TAXATION OFFICE

ATTORNEY GENERAL'S OFFICE Australian Federal Government – Hobart Jan 1982 – Feb 1985

CLERICAL/ADMINISTRATIVE, ACCOUNTS RECEIVABLE/PAYABLE, PETTY CASH

#### KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- Experienced with various development and project management approaches
- Effective Human Capital Management skills
- Analytical skills and attention to detail
- Excellent written and oral communication skills
- In-depth experience with various operating systems, desktop environments and applications, various DBMS, application languages

### **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

OpenClassrooms (Web Front-End Developer): August 2017 - present

Understanding the Web Build Your Website with HTML5 and CSS3 Build Quick and Beautiful WordPress Sites Learn to Code with JavaScript

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

Glenn Bayes Carrer de La Vinya 14 Sant Miquel de Guanteres BARCELONA 08232

T: 937 882943 M: 659 255644 E: gbayes@mac.com

DOB: 26-May-1964 Driving license: Yes

Nationality: Australian/British Settlement: NIE registered Elizabeth Matriculation College – Australia 1980 – 1981 (University Entry) – Chemistry, Advanced Chemistry, Physics, Algebra & Geometry, English Studies, Australian History, Japanese